Guide to the Keith-McHenry-Pond Family Papers, 1841-1961
The Bancroft Library.
- National Council of Women Voters
  - Letter, Mar. 20, 1914, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by A. S. Duniway, Honorary President. (Box 10)
- National Woman's Party
  - 13 letters, 1941-1945 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Laura M. Berrien, Jennie Scott Griffiths, Caroline Lexow Babcock and others. (Box 10)
- Neuhaus, Eugen, 1879-1963
  - Postcard, May 25, 1906, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 6 letters, 1926-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Several letters relate to his book about Keith. (Box 10)
  - 2 letters, 1929-1937, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letter, 1929, lists Keith paintings owned by the University of California at Berkeley. (Carton 5)
- Newhall, Scott, 1914- See San Francisco Chronicle
- Olney, Warren, 1841-1921
  - Letter, May 14, 1903, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written while Mayor of Oakland. (Box 10)
- Olney, Warren, 1870-1939
  - 2 letters, 1911-1913, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1913, concerns copyright on Keith's paintings. (Box 10)
- O'Ryan, Lillie V.
  - 10 letters, 1927-1933, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Several letters concern a portrait of Keith which she painted. (Box 10)
- Otis, James [William Keith's nephew]
  - 13 letters, 1911-1945 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 10)
  - 2 letters, 1948 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Pacific Aero Club, Inc., San Francisco
  - 2 letters, 1917, to Charles Fremont Pond. Letter, Apr. 10, transmits notification of honorary life membership. Letter, May 7, transmits notification of election to the presidency. (Carton 6)
- Paine, William Harris
  - 12 letters, 1880-1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Oct. 20, 1880, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Pardee, George Cooper, 1857-1941
  - Letter, Feb. 21, 1898, to William Keith. Asking Keith to support his candidacy for Governor of California. Includes draft of reply written for him by Mrs. Keith asking Pardee's views of suffrage for women. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Jan. 5, 1933, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With this: note and Christmas card, 1931 and n.d., from Mrs. Pardee. (Box 11)
- Park, Alice Locke
  - 148 letters, 1909-1947 and n.d., primarily to Mary (McHenry) Keith; several addressed to others. Re woman suffrage. With these: notes and quotations re woman suffrage, equal rights, etc. (Box 11)
  - Letter, May 31, 1914, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Thanking her for sending a copy of her book. (Box 16)
  - 19 letters, 1938-1953 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 4 letters (copies) to Brother Cornelius. Re his biography of Keith. (Carton 9)
- Parsons, Marion (Randall), 1878-1953
  - Letter, 1931, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Perkins, George Clement, 1839-1923
  - Letter, Dec. 18, 1911, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written while U.S. Senator from California. (Carton 6)
- Phelps, Alonzo
  - Letter, Jan. 1, 1879, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Commenting on her book The Wandering Jew. With this: copy of his review of her book and letter written by his wife. (Box 16)
- Pierce, Francesca
  - 7 letters, 1910-1911 and n.d. Written primarily while Secretary, Woman Suffrage Party of California, to J. V. McBean. (Box 11)
- Political Equality League, Los Angeles
  - 3 letters, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, Apr. 22, transmits resolution re death of William Keith. (Box 11)
- Polk, Christine (Barreda) [Mrs. Willis Polk]
  - Letter, June 22, 1935, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Polk, Willis, 1865-1924
  - Letter, June 12, n.y., to William Keith. Copy. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Jan. 2, 1924, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for him, thanking her for sending an article about William Keith. (Box 11)
- Pomeroy, John Norton
  - Letter, May 21, 1881, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Pond, Ambia Corson, 1859-
  - Letter, Aug. 2, 1899, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Pond, Charles Fremont, 1856-1929
  - Letter, May 31, 1897, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 3 letters, 1895-1916, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - 45 letters, 1895-1925 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 390 letters, 1882-1916 and n.d., to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
  - Letter, June 12, 1929, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
  - 10 letters, 1895-1907, to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
  - 2 letters, 1896-1916, to John Enoch Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Charles McHenry, 1882-1944
  - 2 letters, 1901-1902, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Dec. 5, 1901, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 2 letters, 1905-1908, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 3 letters, 1907, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 5 letters, 1928-1939, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 7)
  - 3 letters, 1938-1940, to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, Oct. 26, 1943, to Mary Virginia (Pond) Culbertson. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Charles McHenry, 1922-
  - 14 letters, 1945-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
  - 48 letters, 1942-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. With these: 2 letters, 1948-1954, written by his wife. (Carton 5)
  - 448 letters, 1936-1961, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
  - 22 letters, 1934-1944, to his father, Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Elizabeth Keith, 1886-1955
  - 26 letters, 1897-1909, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 42 letters, 1897-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Many letters concern Brother Cornelius biography of William Keith. (Box 11)
  - Letter, Nov. 18, 1899, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Apr. 27, 1932, to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
  - Letter, June 25, 1900, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 8 letters, 1901-1908, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 8 letters, 1947-1955, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, Mar. 18, 1939, to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
  - 3 letters, 1936-1940, to Charles McHenry Pond, [Jr.] (Carton 8)
  - 2 letters, 1943-1944, to Mary Virginia (Pond) Culbertson. (Carton 8)
  - 107 letters, 1933-1955, to Brother Cornelius. Primarily typed copies. Relating to her Keith Miscellanea, her assistance with his biography of Keith, establishment of the Keith gallery at St. Mary's College, etc. (Carton 9)
- Pond, Emma (McHenry), 1857-1934 [Mrs. Charles Fremont Pond]
  - 11 letters, 1855-1899 and n.d., to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 23 letters, 1885-1916 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
  - 166 letters, 1883-1917 and n.d., to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Nov. 6, 1889, to Barbara Allen (Harris) Metcalfe. (Box 18)
  - 5 letters, 1885-1886 and n.d., to Elizabeth Harris (McHenry) Lamare. (Box 19)
  - 4 letters, 1888-1897 and n.d., to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. (Box 21)
  - 2 letters, 1901, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letter, Dec. 26, is copy. (Carton 5)
  - 17 letters, 1909-1916, to Charles Fremont Pond. With these: excerpts (typed transcripts) from her letters to Pond, 1879-1904, which refer to William Keith. (Carton 6)
  - 2 letters, 1904 and n.d., to Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Enoch, 1810-1892
  - 4 letters, 1880-1884, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 4 letters, 1880-1882, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Pond, George Enoch, 1847-1907
  - 11 letters, 1880-1902, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 9 letters, 1880-1882, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. With these: 2 letters written by his wife, 1881-1882. (Carton 6)
- Pond, Inez Virginia (Henderson), d. 1961 [Mrs. Charles McHenry Pond]
  - 22 letters, 1931-1947 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
  - Letter, n.d., to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
  - 42 letters, 1942-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Letter, 1942, is copy. (Carton 5)
  - 2 letters, 1927, to her husband, Charles McHenry Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, Sept. 10, 1943, to Charles McHenry Pond, [Jr.]. (Carton 8)
  - 2 letters, 1940 and n.d., to Mary Virginia (Pond) Culbertson. (Carton 8)
- Pond, John Clark, 1853-
  - 11 letters, 1884-1916, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - Letter, Dec. 7, 1880, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Pond, John Enoch, 1884-1941
  - Letter, Oct. 20, 1901, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Copy. (Carton 5)
  - 4 telegrams, 1903-1905, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
  - Letter, Mar. 5, 1935, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. With this: 2 letters, 1942-1954, written by his wife Wilmac (Harrison) Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, John Enoch, 1914-
  - 6 letters, 1947-1952, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 4 letters, 1955-1956, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, July 12, 1957, to Charles McHenry Pond, [Jr.]. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Louise Mohr (Obenauf) [Mrs. Charles McHenry Pond]
  - 76 letters, 1947-1961 and n.d., to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
  - Letter, Dec. 26, 1957, to Mary Virginia (Pond) Culbertson. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Robert McHenry
  - 3 letters, 1944-1952, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Oct. 7, 1955, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, Sarah Ann (Utley), 1818-1903
  - Letter, Apr. 10, 1881, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. (Box 16)
  - Letter, Dec. 29, 1898, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - 9 letters, 1895-1896 and n.d., to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 5 letters, 1880-1882, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. (Carton 6)
- Pond, Theodore Dwight, 1842-1925
  - 34 letters, 1881-1925, to Charles Fremont Pond. (Carton 6)
  - 2 letters, 1881-1916, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. With these: 5 letters written by his wife, 1880-1881. (Carton 6)
- Pond, Wallace Lemly, 1872-1956
  - 13 letters, 1943-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. With these: Christmas card, n.d., and announcement of his wife's death, 1954. (Carton 5)
  - 13 letters, 1934-1949, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, William Martin, 1916-
  - 2 letters, 1944-1954, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Sept. 12, 1956, to Inez (Henderson) Pond. (Carton 8)
- Pond, William Russell, 1884-
  - 13 letters, 1944-1955 and n.d., to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
- Porter, Bruce, 1865-1953
  - Letter, [1908?], to Joseph Worcester. In Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Carton 9)
- Powers, Laura Bride, 1867-1947
  - 3 letters, 1925-1927, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re sale of some Keith paintings. (Box 11)
- Priestley, Herbert Ingram, 1875-1944 See Bancroft Library
- Putnam, Lucy Chase [Mrs. Osgood Putnam]
  - 2 letters, 1933-1934, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re possible sale of her Keith paintings. (Box 11)
- Putnam, Olivia
  - 3 letters, 1890 and n.d., to William Keith. (Box 3)
- Putnam, Osgood
  - Letter, Sept. 20, 1913, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Putnam's (G. P.) Sons
  - 9 letters (copies), 1940-1943 and n.d., to Brother Cornelius. With these: estimate for printing his biography of Keith, 1940. (Carton 9)
- Putzker, Albin
  - 2 letters, 1885-1907, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. Letter, 1885, is a copy. (Box 19)
- Rainey, Edward See San Francisco. Mayor
- Reese, Patsy McGill
  - 9 letters, 1940-1945 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Reinstein, Jacob Bert, 1853-1911
  - Letter, Oct. 4, 1892, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Richardson, Mary (Curtis), 1848-1931
  - 4 letters, 1912-1915, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
  - Letter, Mar. 15, 1931, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Re her friendship with William Keith beginning in 1868. (Carton 5)
  - Letter (copy), Jan. 22, 1931, to Brother Cornelius. Thanking him for sending a copy of his article about Keith. (Carton 9)
- Richardson, Maud (Wilkinson) [Mrs. Leon Josiah Richardson]
  - Letter, Aug. 8, 1899, to William Keith. (Box 3)
- Rising, Alice
  - 3 postcards, 1909-1911 and n.d., to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 31 letters, 1919-1946 and n.d, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Rising, Lawrence
  - 2 postcards, 1911, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 2 letters, 1911 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 11)
- Rolph, James, 1869-1934 See San Francisco. Mayor
- Roosevelt, Eleanor (Roosevelt), 1884-1962
  - 2 letters (copies), 1940-1941, to Brother Cornelius. Letter, 1940, written for her by her secretary. Letter, 1941, concerns her upcoming visit to the Keith gallery at St. Mary's College. (Carton 9)
- Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1882-1945
  - Letter, June 26, 1916, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written while Assistant Secretary of the Navy. (Carton 6)
- Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919
  - Letter, Oct. 25, 1901, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for him by his secretary. (Box 11)
- Rosecrans, William Starke, 1819-1898
  - 2 letters, 1882, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. Letter, July 26, written for him by his secretary. Acting, as congressman, on her behalf, with respect to a claim handled by Dept. of State. (Box 21.)
- Rosenthal, Toby E., 1848-1917
  - Letter, Aug. 23, 1872, to [Benjamin Parke?] Avery. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- San Francisco. Golden Gate International Exposition, 1939-1940 See also: Amundsen, Jane
  - 5 letters, 1939-1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With these: loan agreements for two Keith paintings. (Box 12.)
- San Francisco. Mayor
  - Letter, Mar. 12, 1915, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written for James Rolph by his secretary, Edward Rainey. Notifying Pond of his appointment as a member of the reception committee for the Vice President. (Carton 6)
- San Francisco. Museum of Art
  - Letter, Dec. 13, 1938, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Grace Morley, Director. (Box 12)
  - Letter (copy), Oct. 7, 1937, to Brother Cornelius. Written by Grace Morley, Director. (Carton 9)
- San Francisco. Panama Pacific International Exposition, 1915
  - Letter, June 25, 1915, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written for the President by Theodore Hardee. Transmits invitation to participate in Woodrow Wilson Day. See also: P.P.I.E. invitations, programs, etc. in Pond family papers. (Carton 9)
- San Francisco Chronicle
  - 15 letters, 1928-1938 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written mainly by E. G. Fitzhamon. Letter, Nov. 17, 1938, written by Scott Newhall. Relate primarily to photographs and other material she supplied for articles about William Keith and others. (Box 12)
- San Francisco Conservatory of Music
  - 9 letters, 1938-1953, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by Ada Clement and Lillian Hodghead. Some are form letters. Letter, June 15, 1939, addressed "To whom it may concern," lists courses E. K. Pond completed at the Conservatory. (Carton 5)
- San Joaquin Pioneer Museum
  - 2 letters, 1947, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by Earl Rowland, Director. Re a Keith exhibition at the Museum. (Carton 5)
- Sather, Jane (Krom), 1824-1911
  - Letter, Mar. 12, 1906, to William Keith. Thanking him for sending her a picture. (Box 3)
  - 3 letters, 1910-1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
- Save-the-Redwoods League
  - 4 letters, 1928-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by Aubrey Drury and J. D. Grant. (Box 12)
- Schaefer, Minerva (Harmon) [William Keith's granddaughter]
  - 10 letters, 1911-1942, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
  - 3 letters, 1931-1942, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter (copy), Mar. 2, 1943, to Brother Cornelius. (Carton 9)
- Schiff, Jacob Henry, 1847-1920
  - 2 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Re reproducing his Keith painting lost in the earthquake and fire. (Box 3)
- Schlingheyde, Clara M.
  - 4 letters, 1901-1903, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written for the California Woman Suffrage Association and The California Equal Suffrage Association. (Box 12)
- Scott, Irving Murray, 1837-1903
  - Letter, May 23, 1894, to Joseph Worcester. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Scott, William Anderson, 1813-1885
  - 4 letters, 1878-1883, to Ellen Josephine (Metcalfe) McHenry. Re the sale of her book. (Box 16)
- Sellers, Alfred H.
  - 2 letters, 1899, to William Keith. (Box 3)
- Seward, George Frederick, 1840- See U.S. Legation. Peiking
- Shaw, Anna Howard, 1847-1919 See also: National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - 17 letters, 1905-1913 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some letters written while President, National American Woman Suffrage Association. (Box 12.)
- Shinn, Joseph Clark
  - Letter, Oct. 3, 1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re death of his sister, Milicent Shinn. (Box 12)
- Shinn, Milicent Washburn, 1858-1940
  - 9 letters, 1911-1940, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
- Smithsonian Institution
  - 3 letters, 1889-1890, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written by G. B. Goode, Assistant Secretary. Thanking Pond for sending specimens of rocks, minerals and shells. With these: 3 acknowledgments of his gifts, 1888-1890. (Carton 6)
- Society For the Prevention of Cruelty To Animals
  - 3 letters, 1911-1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1911, transmits resolution adopted following the death of William Keith. Letter, July 16, 1945, concerns her application for perpetual membership. (Box 12)
- Society of California Pioneers
  - 2 letters, 1929, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by S. C. Oddie, Acting Curator. Re publishing an article about William Keith. (Box 12)
- Sproul, Ida A. (Wittschen), 1891- [Mrs. Robert Gordon Sproul]
  - Letter, May 7, 1945, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Transmitting membership dues for the Keith Art Association. (Box 12)
- Sproul, Robert Gordon See California. University. Comptroller California. University. President
- State Humane Association of California
  - 10 letters, 1939-1948, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written by C. W. Friedrichs, Secretary. Several are form letters requesting membership renewal. With these: list of officers and directors, n.d. (Box 12)
- Stendahl, Earl L.
  - Letter, July 7, 1926, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re authenticating several Keith paintings. (Box 12)
- Stewart, Frances (McHenry), 1898-
  - 6 letters, 1928-1944 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
- Stewart, John Archer
  - 8 letters, 1943-1944 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With these: circular re his insurance business. (Box 12)
- Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1843-1909
  - 2 letters, 1906, to William Keith. Letter, June 1, comments on possessions lost by Ina Coolbrith and Keith in the earthquake and fire. The other letter is a fragment only. (Box 3)
- Storey, Laura (Rice) Roe
  - 3 letters, 1910, to William Keith. (Box 3)
- Swett, Frank Tracy, 1869-1969
  - Letter (copy), Sept. 17, 1935, to Brother Leo. In Miscellaneous Correspondence (Carton 9)
- Taylor, B. Grant, 1872-
  - Letter, Oct. 6, 1927, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
- Taylor, Edward Robeson, 1838-1923
  - 2 letters, 1909-1910, to William Keith. (Box 3)
  - 2 letters, 1903-1904, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. With these: his obituary. (Box 12)
  - Letter, Oct. 27, 1900, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. (Box 19)
  - Letter, May 21, 1916, to Emily Parsons Babcock Hay. (Box 21)
- Taylor, Lucretia (Watson), 1873-1913 [Mrs. B. Grant Taylor] See also: California Equal Suffrage Association
  - 13 letters, 1903-1912 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Relate primarily to the California Equal Suffrage Association. (Box 12.)
- Terhune, Albert Payson
  - Letter, Oct. 11, 1938, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Thanking her for sending a poem for his newspaper column. (Box 12)
- Thomas, Charles Mitchell, 1846-1908 See U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
- Tilden, Douglas, 1860-1935
  - 3 letters, 1931, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re his bust of Keith. (Box 12)
- Todd, Marion
  - Letter, June 1, 1882, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Congratulating her upon her admission to the Bar. (Box 12)
- Tumulty, Joseph Patrick, 1879- See Wilson, Woodrow
- Underhill, Reuben Lukens See Bancroft Library
- U.S. Coast and Geodetic Survey
  - 4 letters, 1886-1889, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written by W. H. Brownson, C. M. Thomas and others. (Carton 6)
- U.S. Dept. of State
  - 8 letters, 1879-1886, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay and to others. Letter, July 24, 1882, is a copy. Re family claims against China. (Box 21)
- U.S. Legation. Peiking
  - 4 letters, 1877-1881, to Mary Emma Zuleika (Metcalfe) Hay. Written mainly by G. F. Seward. Re family claims against China. (Box 21)
- U.S. Secretary of the Navy
  - 2 letters, 1914-1915, to Charles Fremont Pond. Written by Josephus Daniels. Letter, 1915, is a copy. (Carton 6)
- United States Playing Card Company
  - 5 letters, 1914-1915, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Re manufacturing her card game "Constitution." (Carton 6)
- Upton, Harriet Taylor See also: National American Woman Suffrage Association
  - 4 letters, 1910-1912, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Letter, 1910, written while Treasurer, National American Woman Suffrage Association. Letter, 1912, written while President, Ohio Woman Suffrage Association. (Box 12.)
- Varni, Alice (Keith), 1895- [William Keith's granddaughter]
  - 52 letters, 1929-1946, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. (Box 12)
  - Letter, July 24, 1932, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. With this: letter written by her husband, Mar. 14, 1944. (Carton 5)
- Vickery Atkins and Torrey
  - 4 letters, 1890-1906 and n.d., to William Keith. Written by H. Atkins and W. K. Vickery. Re sale of Keith paintings. Letter, Jan. 31, 1906, has several pencil sketches on the verso. (Box 3)
- Wall, Benjamin P.
  - 7 letters, 1893-1908 and n.d., to William Keith. With these: letter, Apr. 21, 1907, written by his sister, Lillie B. Wall.
- Warren, Earl See California. Governor
- Waterman, Sylvanus Dexter, 1842-
  - Letter, May 7, 1901, to Emmanuel Benjamin Lamare. (Box 19)
- Watson, Elizabeth (Lowe), 1843-1927 See also: California Equal Suffrage Association
  - 83 letters, 1909-1927 and n.d., to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written mainly while President, California Equal Suffrage Association. Letter, Oct. 16, 1926, written for her by her brother, A. H. Lowe. Letter, [Feb. 10, 1927] written on verso of letter to her. With these: poem (copy) written about her by her brother, 1926. (Box 12.)
- Webb, E. T.
  - 5 letters, 1910, to William Keith. Re authenticating and repairing several Keith paintings. (Box 3)
  - Letter, Feb. 4, 1911, to E. N. Harmon. With this: letter (copy), Sept. 29, 1910, from Harmon to Webb. (Box 3)
- Western Club of Artists and Artisans
  - 2 letters, 1946, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Written by P. R. Shailer. (Carton 5)
- Wheeler, Benjamin Ide, 1854-1927
  - 2 letters, 1904-1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written while President, University of California. Letter, 1904, is a reply to her suggestion for having women speakers at University meetings. (Box 13)
- Whitney, Charlotte Anita, 1867-1955 See College Equal Suffrage League
- Whitney, Margaret (Mason), 1877-1953
  - 8 letters, 1916-1947, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Some written for the Cragmont Improvement Club. Mainly re erecting a Keith memorial and/or museum in the Berkeley Hills. (Box 13)
  - 20 letters, 1944-1945, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. Some letters written while President, Keith Art Association. (Carton 5)
  - Letter (copy), Mar. 6, 1945, to Brother Cornelius. Written while President, Keith Art Association. (Carton 9)
- Wilkinson, Warring, 1834-1918
  - Letter, Apr. 14, 1911, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re William Keith's death. (Box 13)
- Williams, John Harvey, 1864-
  - Letter, Feb. 12, 1916, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. (Carton 5)
  - Letter, Apr. 28, 1921, to Elizabeth Keith Pond. In Mountain Journal, v. 3 (Carton 11)
- Wilson, Woodrow, 1856-1924
  - Letter, May 26, 1916, to Emma (McHenry) Pond. Written for him by his Secretary, J. P. Tumulty. (Carton 6)
- Wolfe, Linnie (Marsh), 1881-1945
  - 4 letters, 1938-1941, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Written while Secretary, John Muir Association. With these: Association Bulletin-Letter, Apr. 4, 1939. (Box 13)
  - 3 letters (copies), 1941-1942, to Brother Cornelius. (Carton 9)
- Woman Suffrage Party of California See Pierce, Francesca
- Worcester, Alfred
  - Letter, July 4, 1913, to Mary (McHenry) Keith. Re his uncle, Joseph Worcester. (Box 13)
- Worcester, Benjamin
  - Letter, Sept. 23, 1895, to Joseph Worcester. In Miscellaneous Correspondence. (Carton 9)
- Worcester, Joseph, 1836-1913 See also: Herrin, William Franklin Porter, Bruce Scott, Irving Murray Worcester, Alfred Worcester, Benjamin